Heezen-Tharp collection: Arctic Ocean
Geography and Map Division, Library of Congress
- Series II: Arctic Ocean
  - Group 14 - Arctic Ocean Contours, 17660518
    - b0005 Contour Map of Polar Region Washington, DC: National Geographic Society. (Folder Barcode: 00275706681)
      a. Plastic b. Hand colored land mass including Arctic Ocean contours.
    - b0006A [Composite Contour Map of Polar Region] (Folder Barcode: 00275706681)
      a. Ozalid. b. Un-annotated base map covering Quadrants I, II, III, and IV showing drainage and contours on the land and bathymetry.
    - b0006B [Kamchatka Contour Map of Polar Region] (Folder Barcode: 00275706681)
      Sheet 1.
    - b0006C [Scandinavia Contour Map of Polar Region] (Folder Barcode: 00275706681)
      Sheet 2.
    - b0006D [Alaska/Canada Contour Map of Polar Region] (Folder Barcode: 00275706681)
      Sheet 3.
    - b0006E [Greenland Contour Map of Polar Region] (Folder Barcode: 00275706681)
      Sheet 4.
    - b0007 [Preliminary Contour Map of the Mid-Arctic Region] (Folder Barcode: 00275706693)
      Assumed sound velocity - 1500 meters per second. 4 inches equals 1˚ longitude. Contour interval - 200 meters (uncorrected). Arctic Acoustic Project, Gibbs Survey Area, 1971.
    - b0008 [Contour Map of Arctic Region] U.S. Naval Research Laboratory, 1˚ longitude equals 8 inches. (Folder Barcode: 00275706693)
      a. Ozalid. b. Project 71-01-07, U.S. Navy Ship J.W. Gibbs. 76˚ 30 ' to 77˚ 40" North and 4˚ 30' to 8˚ 30' East. Notes: "Contour interval equals 100 meters. Mercator projection. Control-NAVSAT and LORAN 'C'. Depth in meters. Art Molloy."
    - b0009 Arctic Base Negative (Folder Barcode: 00275706693)
      a. Film negative.
    - b0010 [Arctic Ocean Basin Contour Map, 1975 - Quadrant III (Left Half)] (Folder Barcode: 00275706693)
      a. Ozalid. b. Includes feature names and elevations. Note: "John Hall's thesis, 1970."
    - b0011 [Arctic Ocean Basin Contour Map, 1975 - Quadrant III (Right Half)] (Folder Barcode: 00275706693)
    - b0012 [Arctic Ocean Basin Contour Map, 1975 - Quadrant IV] (Folder Barcode: 0027570670A)
      a. Ozalid. b. Notes: "Ed is doing this. AGS has contours for here. New contours are violet."
    - b0013 Arctic Contours (Folder Barcode: 0027570670A)
      a. Linen. b. Polar projection.
    - b0014 Arctic Contours (Folder Barcode: 0027570670A)
      a. Positive transparency. b. Polar projection.
    - b0015 Arctic Ocean Floor Painting Size (Folder Barcode: 0027570670A)
    - b0016 Arctic Contours (Folder Barcode: 0027570670A)
      a. Paper. b. Polar projection. One quarter of the polar series.
  - Group 15 - Arctic Ocean Physiographic Diagrams, 17660540
    1 item
    - c0001 Physiographic diagram of the Arctic Ocean (Folder Barcode: 00275706711)
      a. Paper. b. Oblique Polar projection, with color- coded annotations.
  - Group 16 - Arctic Ocean Province Maps, 17660965
    2 items
    - d0001 Arctic Province Map (Folder Barcode: 00275706723)
      a. Negative print b. Polar projection. Final graphic.
    - d0002 Extension of the Mid-Oceanic Ridge through the Arctic Basin (Folder Barcode: 00275706723)
      a. Negative print. b. Partial Polar projection. Based largely on Soviet data. Epicenters determined during the 1959 geophysical year.
  - Group 17 - Arctic Ocean Worksheets, 17660534
    29 items
    - 0001 [Quadrant Map of the Polar Region] Scale not given. (Folder Barcode: 00275706826)
      a. Paper. b. Worksheet. Colored pencil and pencil notations on Quadrants I, II, III, and IV. Contains status information for each quadrant.
    - 0002 [Arctic Soundings] (Folder Barcode: 00275706826)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Pencil copy of selected soundings for Arctic Sheet II.
    - 0003 Arctic Basin Bathymetry American Geographical Society. (Folder Barcode: 00275706826)
      a. Tracing paper. b. Worksheet with contours at 100, 200, 500, and 1000 meters. Pencil and ink. Covers Arctic Quadrant III.
    - 0004 Arctic Geologic Ages (Folder Barcode: 00275706826)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Colored pencil sketch on polar projection showing continental shelf and suspected continental shelf.
    - 0005 [Arctic Contour Worksheet] (Folder Barcode: 00275706826)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. From 74˚ to 80˚ North and from 5˚ to 12˚ East.
    - 0006 [Arctic Worksheet] (Folder Barcode: 00275706826)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Location unknown.
    - 0007 [Arctic Ocean Basin Contour Map, 1975 - Quadrant I] (Folder Barcode: 00275706838)
      a. Ozalid. b. Hand colored. Preliminary worksheet.
    - 0008 [Arctic Ocean Basin Contour Map, 1975 - Quadrant I] (Folder Barcode: 00275706838)
      a. Ozalid. b. Hand colored. Completed worksheet.
    - 0009 [Arctic Ocean Basin Contour Map, 1975 - Quadrant I] (Folder Barcode: 00275706838)
    - 0010 [Arctic Ocean Basin Contour Map, 1975 - Quadrant I] (Folder Barcode: 00275706838)
      a. Ozalid. b. Completed worksheet. Note: "Added 10 and 100 meter contours 15 July 1974 by M. Casslar."
    - 0011 [Contour Worksheet for Middle Oceanic Ridge and Extension into Arctic Ocean] (Folder Barcode: 0027570684A)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Pencil sketch showing contours in corrected meters.
    - 0012 [Contour Worksheet for Arctic Ocean] (Folder Barcode: 0027570684A)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Oversized, pencil sketch. Note: "Don't color."
    - 0013 [Contour Worksheet for Arctic Ocean] (Folder Barcode: 0027570684A)
      a. Ozalid copy.
    - 0014 [Worksheet for Arctic Ocean Basin Contour Map, 1975 - Area off Spitzbergen] (Folder Barcode: 0027570684A)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Pencil. Large scale.
    - 0015 [Worksheet of Arctic Ocean Basin Contour Map, 1975 - Quadrant II] (Folder Barcode: 00275706851)
      a. Ozalid. b. Colored pencil with color-coded legend showing depths from 0 to 8000.
    - 0016 [Worksheet of Arctic Ocean Basin Contour Map, 1975 - Quadrant II] (Folder Barcode: 00275706851)
      a. Ozalid. b. Hand colored.
    - 0017 [Worksheet of Arctic Ocean Basin Contour Map, 1975 - Quadrant II] (Folder Barcode: 00275706851)
      a. Ozalid. b. Final worksheet.
    - 0018 [Arctic Ocean Contours] (Folder Barcode: 00275706851)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Pen and colored pencil.
    - 0019 [Worksheet of Arctic Ocean Contours] (Folder Barcode: 00275706851)
      a. Tracing paper. b. Location: 68˚ to 72˚ North and 0˚ to 9˚ East.
    - 0020 [Worksheet for Arctic Ocean Basin] (Folder Barcode: 00275706851)
      a. Ozalid. b. Includes legend for symbols and annotations as well as soundings and contours.
    - 0021 [Worksheet for Arctic Ocean Basin Contour Map, 1975 - Quadrant IIIa] (Folder Barcode: 00275706851)
    - 0022 [Preliminary Worksheet for Quadrant III] (Folder Barcode: 00275706863)
      a. Tracing paper. b. Pencil sketches. Notes: "Leave channels on this sheet. Also make sure that abyssal plain boundaries are not dotted. Hank Kutschale's chart and John Hall's chart. No Trespassing. Stay Out!"
    - 0023 [Worksheet for Arctic Ocean Basin Contour Map, 1975 - Quadrant III] (Folder Barcode: 00275706863)
      a. Ozalid. b. Shading with colored pencil. Includes feature names and list of source maps. Note: " Quadrant III, contours copied and checked 6/26/74."
    - 0024 [Worksheet for Arctic Ocean Basin Contour Map, 1975 - Quadrant III] (Folder Barcode: 00275706863)
      a. Ozalid. b. Shading with colored pencil.
    - 0025 [Contour Worksheet for Greenland Abyssal Plain] (Folder Barcode: 00275706875)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Pencil plot.
    - 0026 [Worksheet of Arctic Ocean in Vicinity of Greenland] (Folder Barcode: 00275706875)
      a. Ozalid. b. Include selected soundings and colored pencil annotations.
    - 0027 [Final Drawing Worksheet of Arctic Province Map] (Folder Barcode: 00275706875)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Notes: "Done by Ed Agurkis. June 28, 1974."
    - 0028 [Soundings Across the Reykianes Ridge] (Folder Barcode: 00275706875)
      a. Tracing paper b. From 60˚ to 65˚ North and 22˚ to 30˚ East.
    - 0029 Arctic Worksheet (Folder Barcode: 00275706875)
      a. Tracing paper b. Color-coded contours on a polar projection.
  - Group 18 - Arctic Ocean Photographs, 17760960
    - 0001 [Arctic Panorama] © National Geographic Society (NGS), 1970. (Folder Barcode: 00275706887)
      a. Photograph b. Black and white photograph of artist rendition of Arctic Ocean. See HT II I 3 0017. Note: "Received 3 Dec 70."
    - 0002 [Arctic Panorama] (Folder Barcode: 00275706887)
      a. Film negative. b. Lomonosov Ridge and vicinity.
    - 0003 [Arctic Panorama] (Folder Barcode: 00275706887)
      a. Film positive. b. Black and white photograph of artist rendition of Arctic Ocean.
    - 0004 [Arctic Ocean Floor] (Folder Barcode: 00275706887)
      a. Film positive. b. 8 1/2 inch x 11 inch black and white photograph of Arctic Ocean.
    - 0005 [Arctic Ocean Floor] (Folder Barcode: 00275706887)
      a. Film positive. b. 24 inch x 30 inch black and white photograph of Arctic Ocean.
  - Group 19 - Arctic Ocean Globes, 17661023
    - 0001A [Artist Rendition of the Northern Hemisphere] (Folder Barcode: 00275706814)
    - 0001B [Artist Rendition of the Northern Hemisphere] 29 Sep 70, Scale not given. (Folder Barcode: 00275706814)
  - Group 20 - Arctic Ocean Publications, 17661002
    30 items
    - 0001 Physiographic provinces of the Norwegian- Greenland Sea G. Leonard Johnson and Bruce C. Heezen (Folder Barcode: 00275706735)
      a. Paper. b. Black circles indicate earthquake epicenters, page 756. Note: "Bill: Here's one of the items Bruce mentioned. Leo B."
    - 0002 [Profile of Arctic Abyssal Plain] Heezen and Laughton, 1962. (Folder Barcode: 00275706735)
      a. Frosted acetate with grid. b. Profile from Point Barrow, Alaska across the North Pole to the Greenland- Spitsbergen Straits. Depths - 0 to 3000 fathoms.
    - 0003 Bering Sea Shelf Alaska Reston, VA: U.S. Geological Survey, Department of the Interior; M.S. Marlow, T.R. Alfa, D.W. Scholl, and E.C. Buffington; Open-file 75-1 Map, Sheet 2. (Folder Barcode: 00275706735)
      a. Ozalid. b. Cutaway views of physiography and sub- surface sedimentary and basement sections of the Bering Shelf.
    - 0004 Seismicity of the Arctic ESSA, 1961 - Sept. 1969. (Folder Barcode: 00275706735)
      a. Paper print. b. Polar projection. Coast and Geodetic Center epicenters plotted.
    - 0005A Arctic Seismicity (1908-1975) Ottawa, Canada: Surveys and Mapping Branch, Department of Energy, Mines and Resources; EPB Publication, Vol. 45, No. 4, Plate No. 2; 1978; 1:7,500,000. (Folder Barcode: 00275706735)
      a. Film negative. b. Notes: " Please just use circled earthquakes. All of these are shallow focus earthquakes."
    - 0005B Arctic Seismicity (1908-1975) Ottawa, Canada: Surveys and Mapping Branch, Department of Energy, Mines and Resources; EPB Publication, Vol. 45, No. 4, Plate No. 2; 1978; 1:7,500,000. (Folder Barcode: 00275706735)
      a. Film positive. b. Notes: " Please just use circled earthquakes. All of these are shallow focus earthquakes."
    - 0006 Arctic Mid-Ocean Ridge Nature Magazine, Johnson and Heezen, 12 Aug 67. (Folder Barcode: 00275706735)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Preliminary sketch. Note: "This one wrong way."
    - 0007 Arctic Base Negative Atlas Geologique du Monde - No. 21 - Arctique. (Folder Barcode: 00275706735)
    - 0008 Bathymetric Sketch Map of the Norwegian- Greenland Sea (Folder Barcode: 00275706735)
      a. Paper. b. Figure 11.
    - 0009 Explanatory Notes, Sheet 19 - Arctic (Folder Barcode: 00275706735)
      a. Paper. b. Part 1 - The Oceans by G. Leonard Johnson and Marie Tharp. Part 2 - Description and Interpretation of Salient Geologic Features of the Arctic by Michael Churkin Jr.
    - 0010 “Repartition des points de recherches oceanographiques des expeditions aeriennes de haute latitude” (Folder Barcode: 00275706735)
      a. Positive print. b. Polar projection, showing data for 1937, 1941, 1948 – 1950, and 1954 – 1958. By A.F. Laktionov.
    - 0011a Arctic Study (Folder Barcode: 00275706735)
      a. Paper. b. Plate 2 three dimensional fence model of depth soundings in the Arctic Basin. Page 27.
    - 0011b Arctic Study (Folder Barcode: 00275706735)
      a. Paper. b. Figure 2, locations of the echograms used in the study. Page 19.
    - 0011c Arctic Study (Folder Barcode: 00275706735)
      a. Paper. b. Figure 8, the Lena Trough. Page 60.
    - 0011d Arctic Study (Folder Barcode: 00275706735)
      a. Paper. b. Figure 9a, the Arctic Rises, page 77.
    - 0011e Arctic Study (Folder Barcode: 00275706735)
      a. Paper. b. Figure 9b, Chukchi shelf.
    - 0011f Arctic Study (Folder Barcode: 00275706735)
      a. Paper. b. Arctic Mid-Ocean Ridge.
    - 0011g Arctic Study (Folder Barcode: 00275706735)
      a. Paper. b. The Lomonsov Ridge.
    - 0011h Arctic Study (Folder Barcode: 00275706735)
      a. Paper. b. Continental Slope and Continental Rise.
    - 0011i Arctic Study (Folder Barcode: 00275706735)
      a. Paper. b. The Alpha Rise.
    - 0011j Arctic Study (Folder Barcode: 00275706735)
      a. Paper. b. Summary of Geophysical data.
    - 0011k Arctic Study (Folder Barcode: 00275706735)
      a. Paper. b. Figure 18, Track of the Nautilus 1957 expedition.
    - 0011l Arctic Study (Folder Barcode: 00275706735)
      a. Paper. b. Figure 20, Track chart of the Nautilus 1958 expedition. Page 191.
    - 0011m Arctic Study (Folder Barcode: 00275706735)
      a. Paper. b. Figure 22, Track chart of the SKATE 1958 expedition.
    - 0011n Arctic Study (Folder Barcode: 00275706735)
      a. Paper. b. Figure 24, Track chart of the SKATE 1959 expedition.
    - 0011o Arctic Study (Folder Barcode: 00275706735)
      a. Paper. b. Figure 26, Track chart of the SARGO 1960 expedition.
    - 0011p Arctic Study (Folder Barcode: 00275706735)
      a. Paper. b. Figure 28, Track of the Seadragon 1960 expedition.
    - 0011q Arctic Study (Folder Barcode: 00275706735)
      a. Paper. b. Figure 30, Track of the SKATE 1962 expedition. Page 201.
    - 0011r Arctic Study (Folder Barcode: 00275706735)
      a. Paper. b. Figure 32, Track of the Seadragon 1962 expedition.
    - 0012 Ice and it’s Drift into The North Atlantic Ocean (Folder Barcode: 00275706735)
      a. Paper. b. Text supplement to pilot chart of the N. Atlantic Ocean, April 1963.
  - Group 21 - Arctic Ocean Published Maps, 17661007
    44 items
    - 0001 Oslo: Utgitt av Det Norske Videnskaps- Akademi (Folder Barcode: 00275706759)
      a. Paper. b. Character of sea bottom shown as rock or boulders, sand, shell, sand and shell, gravels, sand and clay, sand and gravels, clay and mud. Depths and altitudes in meters. Shows sunken rocks and shoals of depths less than 25 m (on sheet VII, 20 m)
    - 0001A Bathymetrical Map in Seven Sheets of the Norwegian Coastal Waters and Adjoining Seas - The Submarine Relief off the Norwegian Coast, Sheet I (Folder Barcode: 00275706759)
    - 0001B Bathymetrical Map in Seven Sheets of the Norwegian Coastal Waters and Adjoining Seas - The Submarine Relief off the Norwegian Coast, Sheet II (Folder Barcode: 00275706759)
    - 0001C Bathymetrical Map in Seven Sheets of the Norwegian Coastal Waters and Adjoining Seas - The Submarine Relief off the Norwegian Coast, Sheet III (Folder Barcode: 00275706759)
    - 0001D Bathymetrical Map in Seven Sheets of the Norwegian Coastal Waters and Adjoining Seas - The Submarine Relief off the Norwegian Coast, Sheet IV (Folder Barcode: 00275706759)
    - 0001E Bathymetrical Map in Seven Sheets of the Norwegian Coastal Waters and Adjoining Seas - The Submarine Relief off the Norwegian Coast, Sheet V (Folder Barcode: 00275706759)
    - 0001F Bathymetrical Map in Seven Sheets of the Norwegian Coastal Waters and Adjoining Seas - The Submarine Relief off the Norwegian Coast, Sheet VI (Folder Barcode: 00275706759)
    - 0001G Bathymetrical Map in Seven Sheets of the Norwegian Coastal Waters and Adjoining Seas - The Submarine Relief off the Norwegian Coast, Sheet VII (Folder Barcode: 00275706759)
    - 0002 Carte Generale Bathymetrique Des Oceans Monaco: Le Bureau Hydrographique International, 1 March 54, 3d Edition, Scale not given. (Folder Barcode: 00275706759)
      a. Paper. b. Depths shown from 0 to over 7000 meters. Feuill B'III.
    - 0003 Bathymetric Chart of the Norwegian Sea and Adjacent Areas Norway: Fiskeridirektoratets Havforkningsinstitut, 1963, Scale bar. (Folder Barcode: 00275706760)
      a. Photograph b. Depth lines for every 100 meters.
    - 0004 The Floor of the Arctic Ocean Physiographic Diagram of the Arctic Ocean Floor, San Diego, California: U.S. Navy Electronics Laboratory, August 1966, Scale bars. (Folder Barcode: 00275706760)
      a. Paper. b. An interpretation based on echograms collected by U.S. Navy nuclear submarines from 1957 to 1962. Approximate vertical exaggeration is 30x horizontal. Viewpoint is 30˚ above projection plane. Earthquake epicenters from 1955 to 1964 are shown in red. Inset drawings of ships and submarines.
    - 0005 Arctic Bathymetry Ottawa: The Canadian Hydrographic Service, 1966-1967, Provisional Edition, #897, 1:2,000,000. (Folder Barcode: 00275706760)
      a. Paper. b. North of 72˚, 90˚ to 180˚ West. Depths in meters. Polar Stereographic Projection. A Centennial Project of the Canadian Hydrographic Service.
    - 0006 Carte Generale Bathymetrique Des Oceans Paris, France: L'Institut Geographique National, 3d Edition, 1 Oct 68, 1:3,000,000. (Folder Barcode: 00275706760)
      a. Paper. b. Projection Stereographique Polaire. Bathymetry shown in blue to 5000 meters and topography shown in yellow to 2000 meters.
    - 0007 [Bathymetric Chart of the Polar Region] Scale not given. (Folder Barcode: 00275706760)
      a. Film positive. b. Shows earthquake epicenters. "Returned Oct 29, '69."
    - 0008 [Artist Rendition of the Arctic Ocean] Washington, DC: © by National Geographic Society, 20 Jul 71, 1:10,011,000. (Folder Barcode: 00275706760)
      a. Paper. b. Color proof. Perspective painting by Heinrich C. Berann and assisted by Heinz Vielkind.
    - 0009 Arctic Ocean Floor Washington, DC: National Geographic Society, 1971, 1:9,757,000. (Folder Barcode: 00275706760)
      a. Paper. b. Based on bathymetric studies of Bruce Heezen and Marie Tharp of the Lamont- Doherty Geological Observatory and the U.S. Naval Oceanographic Office. Painted by Heinrich C. Berann, assisted by Heinz Vielkind, compiled by Leo J. Boberschmidt. Azimuthal Equidistant Projection centered on the North Pole. Vertical scale exaggerated. Arctic Ocean political map on verso.
    - 0010 Global Navigation and Planning Chart - GNC 1 St. Louis, Missouri: Defense Mapping Agency, Aerospace Center, Edition 6, June, 1972, 1:5,000,000. (Folder Barcode: 00275706760)
      a. Paper. b. Base map. Shows cultural features of shorelines, cities, drainage, and airfields. Elevations in feet.
    - 0011 Sheet 14, 1975, 1:5,000,000. (Folder Barcode: 00275706760)
      a. Paper. b. Base map. Bathymetry by Bruce C. Heezen and Marie Tharp, Lamont-Doherty Laboratory, Columbia University. Bathymetry research was supported by the Office of Naval Research. See HT- II - I -10 - 0012.
    - 0012 Sheet 14, 1975, 1:5,000,000. (Folder Barcode: 00275706772)
      a. Paper. b. Base map. Bathymetry by Bruce C. Heezen and Marie Tharp, Lamont-Doherty Laboratory, Columbia University. Bathymetry research was supported by the Office of Naval Research. Includes pencil grid and plots of epicenters for the Norwegian and Greenland Seas. See HT - II - I - 10 - 0011.
    - 0013 General Bathymetric Chart of the Oceans (GEBCO), 5•17 Ottawa, Canada: Canadian Hydrographic Service, 5th Edition, Aug 79, 1:6,000,000. (Folder Barcode: 00275706772)
      a. Paper. b. Polar Stereographic Projection. All titling information in English and French.
    - 0014 Bathymetry of the Arctic Ocean Boulder, Colorado: The Geological Society of America, Map and Chart Series MC-56, 1986, 1:4,704,075. (Folder Barcode: 00275706772)
      a. Paper. b. Polar Stereographic Projection. Naval Research Laboratory-Acoustics Division. R.K. Perry and H.S. Flemming. Depths in corrected meters and land mass elevations shown by hypsometric tints. Magnetic anomaly contours shown on verso.
    - 0015 Bathymetry of the Barents and Kara Seas Boulder, Colorado: The Geological Society of America, 1991, 1:2,313,000. (Folder Barcode: 00275706772)
      a. Paper. b. Map and Chart of Series MCH 047. Primary tracks and earthquake epicenters shown on verso.
    - 0016 Residual Magnetic Anomaly Chart of the Arctic Ocean Region Washington, DC: Naval Research Laboratory and Naval Ocean Research and Development Activity, Sheet 1, Scale not given. (Folder Barcode: 00275706772)
      a. Paper. b. Eleven geologic period inset maps shown at top of map. The aeromagnetic profiles shown were collected by various U.S. Navy research organizations during the period 1972 to 1978. Earthquake epicenters to June, 1980 and seafloor spreading shown on verso.
    - 0017 Geology Map of the Arctic Ocean (UNESCO) Scale not given. (Folder Barcode: 00275706784)
      a. Film negative. b. Conic projection map probably at the same scale of similar maps from Geologic Atlas of the World.
    - 0018A [Arctic Ocean Map] Scale not given. (Folder Barcode: 00275706784)
      a. Film negative. b. Polar projection. Includes selected primary data soundings.
    - 0018B [Arctic Ocean Map] Scale not given. (Folder Barcode: 00275706784)
      a. Film positive. b. Polar projection. Includes selected primary data soundings.
    - 0019A [Bathymetric Chart of the Polar Region] Scale not given. (Folder Barcode: 00275706784)
      a. Film positive. b. Secondary data.
    - 0019B [Bathymetric Chart of the Polar Region] Scale not given. (Folder Barcode: 00275706784)
      a. Ozalid copy. b. Secondary data.
    - 0020 North Atlantic Bathymetric Chart - Nordkapp Area Published by the Hydrographic Office, February 1951, 1:1,768,000. (Folder Barcode: 00275706784)
      a. Frosted acetate.
    - 0021A Geologic Map of the Soviet Arctic Ministry of Geology and Defense NEDR, 1957, 1: 2,500,000. (Folder Barcode: 00275706784)
      a. Paper. b. Sheet 1. Edited by R. P. Vasileva.
    - 0021B Geologic Map of the Soviet Arctic Ministry of Geology and Defense NEDR, 1957, 1: 2,500,000. (Folder Barcode: 00275706784)
      a. Paper. b. Sheet 2
    - 0021C Geologic Map of the Soviet Arctic Ministry of Geology and Defense NEDR, 1957, 1: 2,500,000. (Folder Barcode: 00275706784)
      a. Paper. b. Sheet 3. Contains map legend.
    - 0022 Naval Warfare Planning Chart Base, North Atlantic Region 1 September 1969, Published by Naval Oceanographic Office, Scale not given. (Folder Barcode: 00275706796)
    - 0023 [Contour Map of the Bering Sea] Scale bar. (Folder Barcode: 00275706796)
    - 0024 [Polar Projection] Scale not given. (Folder Barcode: 00275706796)
    - 0025 Bathymetry of the Arctic Region Scale not given. (Folder Barcode: 00275706796)
      a. Paper. b. Note: "Figure 132, depth in fathoms."
    - 0026 Geological World Atlas - Sheet 19 (Folder Barcode: 00275706796)
      a. Paper. b. Polar projection. Published for UNESCO by International Geological Mapping Bureau, Paris. 1:16,000,000
    - 0027 Bathymetric Chart of Arctic Ocean (Folder Barcode: 00275706796)
      a. Positive print. b. Polar projection. Compiled from Soviet sources, 1956. Contains inset of a 1954 Soviet bathymetric chart.
    - 0028 Drifts of Research Expeditions in the central part of the Arctic Basin (Folder Barcode: 00275706796)
      a. Positive print. b. Polar projection. Shows drift of North Pole II ice field from 1950-51. “No one there at this time, so no soundings…”
    - 0029 Black and White version of the Arctic Ocean Floor Map (Folder Barcode: 00275706796)
      a. Positive print. b. Published by the National Geographic society.
    - 0030 Arctic Ocean Floor (Folder Barcode: 00275706796)